### PRANAY TUMMALAPALLI

| +91 8860964474 | pranay.tummalapalli@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranay-tummalapalli/ |

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Embedded software and control systems enthusiast with around 4 years of experience in Medical robotics. Passionate about medicine and how technical advancements can be used to design better patient outcomes. Experience and interest in motor control and robot control. 3 years of experience developing Robotic Laparoscopic surgery and Robotic TKR.

## **SKILLSET**

 Control Systems: PID control and mathematical modeling for motors

- Embedded firmware: RP2040, STM32F4, STM32F3, STM32H7, Atmega2560, ESP32, ESP8266

 Peripherals: Motor Drivers and encoders, Sensors, Bluetooth, EEPROM, IMU, Hall Sensors

 Software/CAD: Eagle CAB, KiCAD, Fusion360 **Programming:** C, shared memory, socket programming, Linux Kernel Development

Communication protocols: SPI, I2C, UART/USART,

EtherCAT, CAN, UDP/TCP

Version control: Git, Bitbucket

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Meril Healthcare (Robotic Endosurgery) Sr. Embedded Firmware Engineer, Linux

(Nov 2023 - Present, 10 months)

- STM32 based solutions for EtherCAT Slave implementation for ASIX58400 based in-house motor drives, RFID Data reading etc. implemented on the system.
- Motor control code for ethercat based Motor drive from Novanta, and Maxon. Developed multi slave code with Distributed Clocks for Robot end-effector actuators.
- Used C in linux for development. Integrated with shared memory and UDP server-client architecture for sharing desired setpoint data to the motor.
- Mathematical modeling of motor and motor and drive characteristics analysis for PID control.
- Integrating **Surgical robotic system for laparoscopic surgery** with touchscreen, x86 single-board-computer, and **optimizing Ubuntu operating system** to run GUI.
- Part selection based on identified system requirements, supplier identification to optimize for cost, lead time and long term support. Found a long term solution with low cost high performance parts.
- Contributed towards the success of the MISSO orthopedic surgical robot and its product launch.
- International Experience: Part of delegation to Shanghai to attend the CMEF 24 and identify potential partners. Converted 2 suppliers to long term partners.
- Part of a team to find **Chinese robotics companies** including humanoids, quadrupeds, rehabilitation exoskeletons, and autonomous vehicles to partner with for **OEM development**. Visited 15 companies across Shanghai, Beijing, Shenzhen, Longyan, Suzhou.
- Quality and Regulatory Experience: Formulated a system BOM for BOM based purchase system and system versioning. Formed requirements for each subsystem and implemented test methods to ensure requirements are met.
- **Organized Cadaver trials** for the laparoscopic and orthopedic robots and implemented **on field research for user validation with surgeons.**

#### E-chai Networks:

- **Organized and Hosted multiple networking events** across Bangalore with 25-30 participants from **hardware**, **manufacturing**, **medical device and robotics startups**.
- Formats included open Q&A, Panel Discussions, and fireside chats.

- incharge of day-to-day R&D with a multidisciplinary team, feature pipelining for Patient Cart, Endoscopic vision and Surgeon's console
- Incharge of multidisciplinary design of Surgeon's console including usability, electronics, master-slave forward kinematics using DH Parameters, ergonomics etc.
- PID based control system for BLDC control with magnetic encoder.
- Implemented ESD, EMI/EMC protection in the PCBs
- Requirements engineering for the product and usability design, preliminary design for verification and validation tests, and MDR compliance
- End-user validation with Ob/gyn, Urology and GI surgeons.
- Basic understanding of harmonized MDR standards including IEC 60601, ISO 14971 etc.

# Articulus Surgical Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru Mechatronics & Industrial Design Lead:

(Nov 2021 - Jan 2023, 1 yr 2 Months)

- Part of the **founding team** and contribution toward early stage development of **Robotic Surgery System**.
- Developed a prototype for the Surgeon's Console: design and physical analysis of gravity compensation mechanism for a 7-DOF console manipulator; integration with rotary encoders for joint positions; angular monostable positioning of joints
- Platforms and Skills:
  - Autodesk Fusion360 CAD design for complex multi-body assemblies, joint designs, simulations and FEM, rendering tool.
  - FDM 3D Printing: Prusa I3 Mk3, Creality ender 3 v2, CR10Max. Prusa and Cura slicer.
  - SLA 3D Printing: Elegoo Mars 3 and slicer
  - Industrial Design work samples on www.articulussurgical.com
  - DFM 3 axis milling, Lathe/turning, SLS for Titanium, FDM Plastic 3D Printing

# Akshar Bionics (Funded by Ministry of Education), New Delhi (Jan Co-Founder

(Jan 2021 - Oct 2021, 9 Months)

- Used Biomimetic design methodology to develop fully 3D-printed and actuated upper-body robotic arm
- Developed Joint mechanisms and calculated inverse kinematics using DH-Parameters.
- Patents for Software integrated system and robotic arm design for the project pending.
- The project won Smart India Hackathon 2018 (Hardware Edition) and subsequently was granted funding from MOE, GOI.

# Product Internship, Trestle Labs, New Delhi:

(Feb 2020 - July 2020)

- Designed a phone stand to enable visually impaired users to scan and convert hardcopy documents and books into audio format (audiobooks) using Trestle Labs' Kibo XL app.
- Carried out User research and validation testing at NGOs in New Delhi

### **PROJECTS**

# **Vocol, Akshar Bionics**

 Vocol is a system that converts speech input to American Sign Language and Indian Sign Language on a Life-Scale humanoid robot designed using biomimetic design methodology for its joints and limb movements. Servo actuated joints and I2C networked servo controllers controlled by an STM microcontroller.

# LoRa Sensor Network for Accident Prevention, PriorFire

- A Sensor network between multiple cars that classify a car as a danger if the driver doesn't drive properly, and then informs the other cars from a long distance that there is a dangerous driver nearby, increasing their reaction time.
- Used LoRaWAN protocol, Image Processing for drowsiness detection, lane detection using openCV, and position encoder to calculate steering wheel deviation. NodeMCU, LoRa RA-02, LCD, Raspberry pi 3B
- Won 1st prize in Hardware Productathon, E-Summit 2020, IIT-Roorkee

## Smart Object Detection and Guidance Device for Visually Impaired, Raah

A two stage haptic feedback based algorithm to guide a blind person to an object. It uses object recognition in OpenCV using tensorflow and deep learning.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communications**

(Aug 2017 - July 2021)

Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering, New Delhi

- Awarded Best Student (ECE1), Batch of 2017
- (CGPA 7.36)